From the creator of Being John Malkovich, comes the story
about the creator of Being John Malkovich.
Adaptation. is a comedy, crime, drama film directed by Spike Jonze.
Charlie Kaufman is a confused L.A.
screenwriter overwhelmed by feelings of inadequacy, sexual frustration, self-loathing,
and by the screenwriting ambitions of his freeloading twin brother Donald.
While struggling to adapt "The Orchid Thief," by Susan Orlean,
Kaufman's life spins from pathetic to bizarre.
The lives of Kaufman, Orlean's book, become strangely intertwined as
each one's search for passion collides with the others'.
Charlie Kaufman / Donald Kaufman, played by Nicolas Cage.
Susan Orlean, played by Meryl Streep.
John Laroche, played by Chris Cooper.
Valerie Thomas, played by Tilda Swinton.
Matthew Osceola, played by Jay Tavare.
Russell, played by Litefoot.
Adaptation is a 2002 American metafictional comedy-drama film
directed by Spike Jonze and written by Charlie Kaufman.
It features an ensemble cast led by Nicolas Cage, Meryl Streep, and Chris Cooper, with Cara Seymour,
Brian Cox, Tilda Swinton, Ron Livingston, and Maggie Gyllenhaal in supporting roles.
Kaufman based Adaptation on his struggles to adapt Susan Orlean's 1998
nonfiction book The Orchid Thief while suffering from writer's block.
It involves elements adapted from the book, plus fictitious elements, including Kaufman's twin brother (also
credited as a writer for the film) and a romance between Orlean and John Laroche (Cooper).
It culminates in completely invented elements, including versions of Orlean
and Laroche three years after the events of The Orchid Thief.
Adaptation received widespread critical acclaim for its direction,
screenplay, humor, and the performances of Cage, Cooper, and Streep.
It received awards at the 75th Academy Awards, 60th Golden Globe Awards, and 56th British Academy Film Awards, with Cooper
winning the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor and Kaufman winning the BAFTA Award for Best Adapted Screenplay.
A British Film Institute poll ranked it one of the
thirty best films of the 2000s.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, marriage
crisis, alligator, writer's block, orchid.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.